so we talk about danger hmm since since
you're all the same how's funny if we
could take that further to talk about
the danger in the world in general or
like the fabulous sense the 6th Ave the
senses uh-huh yeah
so what are they I would against them so
I've just right here right now as I'm
saying that just said it okay I feel
beautiful so the feeling is a starting point as we
so the feeling is a starting point as we
said millions of times it's a conversion
point but does that mean now you go and
find the other aggregates after you've
established your mind upon feeling oh
well I can't find how do you how do you
descend the other regulator a general
there are five
because you know it's not an explanation
the Buddha never gave explanations
everything he taught was open icon baby
elements to it understand it so how can
then understanding the five leads to the
freedom progression so which five that's
very good question so where would you
look for the other aggregates then well neech failing
have same things favourite things but
wait is that square up one of your
feelings where is it things you feeling
things you see holiday that's the thing
I don't quite know where you're going
but like I don't want to break him down
I was having my tendency would be to
just look ok just as this experience as
a whole
so when you say five minutes you just
referred to it in - that's kind of what
I would say oh yeah no that's absolutely
fine that's what it stands for for you
in at a time but where I was going was
five three one whichever you want to
look it's within the one you might feel
so you wouldn't be looking for the other
aggregates after the feet right the
experience of the feeling enduring is
the experience of the five aggregates
enduring and you emphasize the feeling
because that's the conversion point yeah
in other words they're inseparable when
is one is fine yeah there's five you can
focus on one but the problem is people
start without focusing on one and then
sort of just add up the rest as if it's
all like laid out there for you and you
just have these five things to think
about in this linear manner no I'm
feeling a pleasant feeling that's
enduring here in my experience the whole
my whole experience is basically founded
upon the currently enduring pleasant
agreeable feeling that's already the
experience of the five other ways yeah
even if I don't think about perception
if I don't think about intentions
totally within it yeah you'll find them
within none of you if you were to look
it if you any feel if you find and then
if you find perception within the
container of the present enduring
feeling yeah then you can go further if
your mind develops and then you can you
can discern other for within that
perception yeah including more
perception so it's five within one
within five within one five million five
everybody look five aggregates
yes that's what we said whether you know
the end if you remember previous lives
yeah because when you tell if the
tendency to go okay this is feeling in
that perception exactly you're basically
oh he's just playing in the sand you let
yourself out it's not in the basis of
the experience they're hauling it's
certainly not
you're not mindful of the feeling is
that converging point and when I say
converging point I mean I mean things
converging then go elsewhere though they
converge here and stay within the
container of present enduring feeling
that's how you learn how to think
concretely as well yeah
not linearly or theoretically or
abstractly so how do we clarify that
okay gonna so you were talking about the
danger in sexuality ha
ha
and I think that can also be applied to
okay so basically sitting here neutral
feeling
but that feeling could be change could
change listener has the nature to change
sure so while it indoors you can discern
that it's subject to change exactly
that's with Herman and where that change
comes from this inclusive is completely
seem in thinking that it comes from
something that is the wrong it's a boom
what form of conceiving it yeah this is
in consumer isin every change is abrupt
yeah and I'll be subjected to it and
it's impossible for me to kind of insert
myself in between the abrupt change you
know it's before it's completely that is
the danger that is the danger and the
reason why people would have trouble
grasping the danger of it is because you
still you still think to degree well you
fail to understand that things don't
change when they disappear or when you
perceive that means they have already
changed but you want to see that their
subjective change while they remain the
same so basically most people when they
think about a niche I think about
changes I all look look everything is
constantly changing look look look no
everything is constantly changed do yes
is what you can see but you want to see
you want to see the subject to change I
have that nature is change exactly so
things is not changing them this feeling
is still enduring and because of that
it's subjected to change and whenever
that happens I would be subjected to it
equally sensing I cannot prevent it so
that's what I mean like so recognizing
the feeling that's enduring but also the
whole range of possibility that is
involved in that and because the
presently enduring neither painful nor
pleasant feeling could just change any
minutes into you well paint
Yun's basically part of that that's the
nature of this pro colony even if you
changes the pleasure in still painful
nature because of the change not because
of what changed the fact that you cannot
uproot it in a sense of ownership
you cannot take possession of it at the
word it originates so to speak you're
always secondary to it your experience
as a whole and that's been thrown all
the lifetimes you've been around even
the news the news is always responding
to what you're subjected yeah on your
level of the feelings that's right so
basic answer is responding to what's
there I'm feeling responding to it his
bar is basically sort of going into it
and said I mean accepting it and but not
just accepting the feeling but also it
but accepting this whole sort of nature
of change yes your your new is you're
basically going in and saying I want
this to change exactly but it's because
it has changed that's why I want it to
change so because of the change that I cannot
so because of the change that I cannot
bear change my accent because of the
change that I cannot bear i accept
change yeah did I cannot bear which is why I
yeah did I cannot bear which is why I
want more change did I cannot bear yeah
and it's a vicious circle election yeah
yeah that's why it's unwholesome
that's why I always keep insisting the
darlin if the Dhamma is done as a form
of management and that's determined by
your attitude where they use it to
manage what you feel that's not the
Dhamma yeah yeah yeah you know everybody
will start inaccurately
but if that's all you do and never start
looking for beyond that you're never
gonna surprise us in the Dhamma cuz
Dhamma up basically frees you from being
subjected to that nature yeah Dhamma
doesn't give you a perfect way of
managing your suffering or managing your
feelings and you can only do that by
escaping by finding the escape from yes
from that which is uncle in control
uncontrollable unknowable that is
subject to change so what is the escape
from that see the danger seeing the
danger in what in everything that so
you're not seeing the danger in the
outcome no no no not seeing the danger
will not even like seeing the danger in
what like well there's a pleasant
feeling in your no no no yeah it's the
nature well see the nature has seen the
danger on the level of the nature of
what this is subjected to the whole this
whole this all this presents is so well
there is that nature seen
so if what's in front of you you can't
see the injury just fine I mean you can
fabricate at the end you can tell us all
these sick dangerous yeah the future
prospect and you'll tell you you tell me
yourself is dangerous in order to try to
die services have to get rid of area and
basically got you to try and change it
yeah good we can we can address that
later but what I wanted to ask was so if
you can't see the danger in what's
what's right in front of you yeah as if
the danger is not in the perception of
energy you can't see the danger then in
the result of what's in front you
because they're just gonna be another
perception exactly why is that where do
you look for the dangers peripherally in
regard to what regard see was present
one can say Joey what's present in you
yeah so that's why knowledge peripheral
background I will become basically
synonymous or
that's what understanding takes place
yeah you can examine think through a
perception all you want but you don't
understand what is subjected to now what
is subjected to is that which cannot be
seen on the level of that thing because
it becomes a thing something else is
that subjected to sorry you can't see oh
this thing is subjected to change you
can't say that section of the thing
because it's already second only to his
nature you just can't perceive it like that
you just can't perceive it like that
yeah and if you all you do is perception
perception focusing focusing sensations
sensations nostrils nostril that's why
understanding things first for my
understanding today you understand
feeling by having this and not just that
seeing that seeing that this nature
change and gratefully as you said you
can only see the nature of change once
you stop interfering with a feeling yeah
stop trying to get rid of it and stop
indulging it yeah so stop being
unrestrained and stop trying to deny it through
and stop trying to deny it through
through like overzealous restraint yeah
and hence the middle way so if you
recognize the nature of feeling is to in
do then you can recognize what that
nature or rather you can then recognize
what that endurance is also subjected to
but in order to as I said in order to
recognize this is subject to such and
such qualities characteristics you need
to allow it to be there first enduring
not ever view that it's momentarily
changing arising passing rising passing
arising passing those are completely
separate things it's dead remaining the
same while it is subjected to change
that's how you get to understand and
feel the threat of the change feel the
Dukas all furniture that's in the danger
no though look blue it's changing its
changing that is dukkha isn't it yeah
and that's why if this has to be rooted
in the danger right now of the feeling
yeah is it not after not as a management
not as an explanation and as you said
even when people say over this is
impermanent or the other one the
favorite of this too shall pass that's
another way of trying to get rid of it
yes oh this why would you be telling
oh this why would you be telling
would you be telling to yourself yeah
this too shall pass because you're
basically trying to convince yourself
that the current pain will go away it
will change and while he wants it to
change exactly why why would you want
current pain to go away means you don't
want it to be there yeah means you're
craving again still yeah
so that's our meaningful for many people
practicing the Dharma then becomes just
another form of management which is
another form of denial so it's no more
coping mechanism but in order in order
to the fact that you're coping means you
have to be affected first yeah if your
practice is priced on the level of
coping you cannot possibly approve much
what's affecting you
the so it's not so much that Duker is a
nature that my pain will is impairment
will go away I hope in the future
Zuka it's the other whereas a nature is
dukkha that's what we're never messed
around with the order beginnings it's
always a nature is just experience of
anata is feeling permanent Rosetta is
why is impermanent pleasant or painful
yeah and again why is wise wiring
permanent things unpleasant why is that
which is Anita why is that which is
subject to change
why is it unpleasant what can it be
pleasant
you know we don't want it to change like
it you know I want to change as we said
when you're softer you actually want the
opposite feeling to change wise change
unpleasant doesn't matter if it's change
for better or for worse change in itself
is dukkha why have you say exactly
inconceivable now you can tell yourself
all you want that you have a savior in
control the fact is you are subjected to
change because things change on their
own on their own accord it's completely
inaccessible to you yet you latch on to
it when it feels like it suits you it
suits your needs and then if I think the
natural ice pretty much every the
fundamentalism for any action any common
good I bet it's that you want to change
them that's why you for yourself from
that nature of being subjected to change
you free yourself from action you feel
yourself from acting out of it
are there difference art that
contradiction you free yourself no
comment
because your actions because anything
any all kind of intentions I say and now
of no longer roots it in want to change
once a message and if you say oh this
too shall pass what's gonna happen then
money passes well there's this whatever
I'm worried about impermanence but it
will pass yeah I tell to myself to help
myself cope with it
what's gonna happen afterwards when this
passes something else exactly
so what's gonna happen in something else
just like you're not so then you realize
it like when people do use this coping
mechanism their management techniques
even on the pretext of Dhamma practice
all you can affect this content of
things that bothers you
oh this too shall pass yeah that would
pass something else which take this
place while the nature of being
subjected to change remains unchanged
and you are fully under its thumb
the bullet Oaks thought about turning
away from they've been dirty turning
away from feeling that's like this
passion this passion leads to turning
away one fading away become
dispassionate and cessation liberation
so turning away from feeling well you've
turn away from feeling by turning away
from wanting change yeah that's what I
was that's what I was thinking it's not
so much it's not so much you can do
angrily true students there's any way
you're feeling because yes because
feelings that whether you may be like oh
no but and turning away they're enough
sounds like surely can be taking that
simulate what anybody would say oh he
doesn't tolerate yeah you know the
thought of last story will people think
that to me now you must deny it
yeah no you don't tolerate it means I
don't tolerate this which is their
enduring in front of me but if you try
to deny it as if you're they shouldn't
be there this shouldn't be there you're
overstepping it means you're interfering
which means you're getting hooked again
so it's more setting up in conditions
there will result in turning your way
yeah and those conditions are seeing it
seeing this things that you'll
understand yeah saying this things like
full understanding of nature oh and how
did the Buddha described full
understanding by seeing the extent of
gratification I see in the extent of
danger but seeing the extent to escape
and by the way he didn't use it only for
sensuality no when he was describing all
thank asinus he used the same principle
I've seen he talks about he talks about
seeing the gratification danger escape
from the really far over goes yeah six
domains consciousness the world the
element of Earth yes exactly so the
extent of its gratification as in the
extent of its affirmation enough either
through acceptance or denial you still
affirm it that which you accept to deny
so the extent of danger implicit in you
doing that so so it's not so not so it's
not so much turning
away from feeling is as seeing that this
is something I don't want I don't want
Italy I'm not welcoming not home so if I
don't want this if I don't want to sort
of step into this and once once it want
to engage with it lots of changes
it's important to emphasize that it's
not much it's not the level of choice
nah-ha cannot be on the level of choice
so you don't have to choose to not want
danger you just need to start learn how
to see the danger danger automatically
means no passion no passion
automatically means no desire if there
is no desire there is no wanting if
there is no basis of wanting there is no
basis for craving if there is no craving
in regard to feeling there is no
ownership of feeling thus that's
completely expression removal of any
fire burning in regard to feeling done
understand understanding the danger on
the right level in regard to right
things not secondarily not as a as a
level of management not as an
afterthought not as a linear explanation
everything fits beautifully exam as the
modern science is proven no
understanding why am i subjected to this
danger needs to be personal
so whether is the feeling you're
cultivating where the perception whether
it's the moods
whether it's central cravings whether
it's eel well for that matter whether
it's anything understand the extent of
gratification the extent of danger will
become apparent the escape would be
really the escape means removal of
action and delight in it
and so not delighting in feeling for
example
it's the same thing as not like
why exchange because you know that whole
sort of nature of change that ultimate
of change is well that dangerous depends
said if you say like oh I don't you you
don't want it to change now that can
also mean like you're interfering with
it yeah yeah I want this to be more of
what it is I want this to remain the
same as it is as in I want it to but
again I'm applying another layer of that
feeling so do you think you know wanting
change you're still acting out of change
change that you don't want yeah so
whether you're firm whether you cannot
change you accept revolving around so
you want to see the danger in the change
doesn't matter whether it changes how
quickly when for better or for worse of
changes just to remain the same a bit
more it doesn't matter what matters is
seen the danger in that not in the
content not in the results but in the
nature of being subject to change that's
really sort upon his insight but
basically the inside that qualifies you
that makes your solar panels ah whatever
yeah whatever has a nature to manifest
as in to change on its own to appear on
its own that's why it's impermanent
because of that nature because of the
content because I analyze its atomic
structure and prevented it with
disintegrate because the experience of
disintegration has manifested forth the
experience of destruction has manifested
for you that's not the nature because
the experience of destruction and
destroying these things is of a nature
to change the experience of construction
is it a nature to change so it's just
basically seeing paying off impairments
yes its impermanence is incorrectly it
is felt unpleasantly if if that which is
seen correctly felt unpleasantly that
experience cannot be taken his mind thus
there is no room for after it's funny
how many people start meditating and it
was like a teacher was that high
everything's changing it all just I feel
it's really Pleasant yeah I mean it's a
denial of it isn't it yeah like
nothing's the mother's no father that's
why there's no this doesn't feel like of
everything's just he's no pain because
everything is constantly changing
it's exactly it falls into those some
upon a sort of wrong views that it would
have described yeah yeah nobody dies
nobody leaves everything is constantly
change constant constant state of flux
nothing massive how can you even after a
sentence yeah if everything is constantly
yeah if everything is constantly
changing your sentence will be
meaningless by the time it reaches its
end yeah but it isn't you get the
meaning which is clearly not changing
for you yet you go around saying
everything is changing and that's the
view that doesn't change for you know
that's the villain Jones exactly but you
you enable yourself is an honest view
yeah you enable yourself to deny it by
focusing on the content of things making
a meditation about the content your
mindfulness about staring at the content
so you don't have to look at nature and
basically become aware of your
responsibility for choosing to hold that
view yeah like that man who came to the
Buddha and said the world asking what
view I said well my view is that nothing
pleasingly my view that everything
changes constantly every second of the
time and then the way you can easily say
well that really doesn't change for you
in the same sense he said oh well that
meal pleases you that it nothing pleases
me
so can you even conceive anything then
they will not be subjected to the
changer of change they would not but
take in the nature of danger of change
well no because that anything I conceive
no it's contained within this situation
of me saying yeah well see anything you
can see say anything any thought that
pops up in your head yeah there you go
popping up you cannot create it no it
appears for you yeah can you conceive
anything that it's of a nature to appear
to not share the nature of about to
change because appearance is already a
form of abrupt change thing manifesting
means there's been change yes absolutely
doesn't have assumable yeah yeah you can
regardless no notice or subject to
change that's nothing you've come
conceived conceived anything is
permanent yeah or place that people who
translate or is not dangerous and they
say that the change you want it's always
like the forefront you want things in
the forefront of change but change
actually happens where you can't yeah
that's what me when I say you can only
deal a meant the content that's the
thing so I want a change because you
projected desire onto the content of
what you want to change and that's what
sensuality kind of gets you locked on
sense objects and it's completely not in
them it's in your dependence on that
delight in change yet you think it's in
in the
in the things you can touch see taste
the song that it is not the slightest
not even a grain or it can spill into
the material inconceivable in any case
to change your subjective you try to
conceive that like through the through
the content when you know you're not
trying to conceive it you're conceiving
it basically by overlooking it by
putting it in the content you have miss
conceded any form of misconceiving is
conceiving is there so you miss conceive
it to be there you miss conceived
pleasure to be contained in things in
response to this unpleasant desire you
miss conceived misconceived
misconceiving means contradiction any
misconceiving means conceiving is there
that's why
or you could say conceiving means miss
conceiving and sorrow hunt is free from
conceiving freak for contradictions on
that existential level
then like again it's not like you have
to figure out and sort of you know
constant net its gonna scoop all the
conceiving ZUP no you just need to stop
entertaining fashion through your
ignorant acts for which you responsible
they're always you can't do you can't
get your last aversion delusion
accidentally it's always on the basis of
your choice always you stop feeding
those states of mind through your choice
and you will do so if you find a good
reason to not do it you are then
removing the basis for maintenance of
those misconceiving
that's why Siva has to come first
absolutely not negotiable in any shape
or form
and that's what practice never leaves
that container of sealer so now oh I'm
develop sealing I'll go and figure this
out develop Silla understand it that's it
develop Silla understand it that's it
that woman's figuring now once you
understood the basis of Nam know last
not a version of delusion it's
irreversible you cannot engage
we lost the vision delusion anymore
because to do that is always to
basically want things to change
always always that's why both like which
is meritorious and demerit other
sections but take within comma but take
within this principle of being subjected
to to change in ownership and you crave
for it yeah there's a good action
there's a bad action either way action
is there acting for change is there yeah
can you act out of wanting this to
change if you have no desire no
conceivable desire for this I could
change it that's why you also ties in
with the wrong view that you are the
master controller see you are subjected
to change because of which you won't
change because of which you're acting
and change happens abruptly to you but
it's you start the gardens because you
acted it tense what happens to you but
why did you act in the first place
because you were subjected things you
couldn't prevent so then your action is
secondary your ownership is secondary to
that well basically your ownership is
fully within the container that you
cannot conceive outside of let alone own
and control it but you forget that and
already start singing is me acting and
things changing thus I am Here I am mine
these things I do belong to me I am the
master cause look I can break this I can
create this amount of it to change that
so this but I can change this yeah said
that I'm still in control that's more
than enough again but if you were to ask
yourself honestly so which is more than
things you can't share things not change
I can't change so then your ability to
change is fully enclosed within the vast
sea of
things that you cannot even conceive how
to change so it's secondary and if
ownership is if mastery secondary it's
the master isn't here oh I'm enslaved by
this but I tell myself I'm a master of
this having this sum in this prison cell
but I'm free to walk up there yeah
exactly I can lay I could stand I can
sit I am my own man okay yeah in that
door like the only subject to that when
you think you have a saying what you've
been subjected to this enough yeah that
has to be implicit he has to be in place
that's why you maintain these kind of
implicit views through your careless
action like you have to stop maintaining
so providing basis for those views
through your again volitional choice of
lust diversion and distraction if you
stop maintaining it then yet you won't
be able to feed these implicit beliefs
because yeah if you are not already
implying that you can master that you
can take possession of change you
wouldn't have any desire and lust
towards wanting things to change it
would be inconceivable that's what
freedom from desire lost his freedom
from ownership freedom from the sense of
self that you are always trying to
change something yeah
and that's that's actually was always
the reason for the suffering for the
title exactly is absolute nothing out of
nothing else
that's a suffering freedom from it it's
pretty much a universal goal you have
for people who choose to go about it by
proliferating their suffering and lost
an aversion and distraction and chases
in solitary they still do it for the
reason because they want to be free from
the pain and I'm not having enough of
what you want pain of of having more
than enough for what you don't want but
as the Buddha said pain of being
separated from the things that are
desirable likeable and pain and being
United with things that are unpleasant
anything's perception not just this
thing it's on the level of the nature of
things
yes we have also talked about seeing the
danger the body hmm it's a different
wave so that's a principle yeah
gratification danger escape from the eye
sighs everything exactly which ever
asked the particular aspect of it you
might take the nature the same and
that's what you're supposed to descend
not stay focusing on a particular aspect
it was somehow revealing the truth
magically
so the condition of death quite quite
straightforwardly undermines that isn't
it like yeah yeah sharply it'll be hard
to if you do the contemplation of that
correctly it will be very hard to then
maintain all these misconceiving we're
talking about but then you might be a
bit too much too soon for some people if
they have developer to beforehand
this is the same principle really
talking about death is just that kind of
abrupt change
yeah just different way of arriving at
the discernment of the same principle
basically death is that fundamental
doesn't matter how much I control I can
I can exercise I can apply it's all
within a very very perilous base that is
subjected to ultimate non control death
on each other so if something is
fundamentally cannot escape subject of
abrupt change whichever way is that
something you can deeply regard as oh
this is mine dear to me personal
intimate no although that should require
a degree of well conceived permanence
conceived ownership conceived control
conceived possession the only reason why
you can do that is because you're not
seeing but but it's all underlined by
here
and you're not seeing what it's all
underlined by because you're actively
choosing to ignore it and that's a
vision not a metaphysical Maya veil of
illusion it's a choice to distract
yourself or you're out pleasant truth
yeah exactly because it's more pleasant
to avoid that and focus on the be the
illusion of control where I can give you
the pleasure out to what they Aleppo
getting this inspection the fire and
investing his whole life and building
elaborate fire pits where you can burn
his skin and find enjoyment yeah you do
it basically yeah building a home and
life based on sensuality which is pretty
much everyone's life yeah
while in reality all of it is done
because of pain and fear and in itself
remains painful and fearful
and so you choose to kind of people
choose to to not look at danger though
fear
whereas actually that is what they need
to look at in order to free themselves
for them yeah
they choose to not look at it because
that's the that's the only way of
freedom for me do they know yeah but
it's not the freedom is it a robber
actions yeah it's making it worse yeah Frankie
yeah it's making it worse yeah Frankie
next I'm making even harder to look away
from it so then you have to double down
yeah that's what I mean whether it's a
protrusion or another hunt as the Buddha
said in the Sutra 13 everyone wants to
be free from affliction but only when
you reach like the level of surmounting
sensuality developing the proper
understanding of jhana then you realize
this is truly the beginning of freedom
from affliction nothing less than this
and then there is yeah I always wanted
to be free from affliction that's why I
was engaging with sensuality cuz it was
afflicting me yeah I just tell me why
I'm here you want to go down towards it
so it's like keep
keeping alive
delete delete backspace Facebook
[Laughter]
so even if somebody is overwhelmed
doesn't know how to practice way to
practice what to do just too much all
these aggregates a number of cousin what
not one thing you can doubt for sure is
if I willingly mindfully carefully
choose to not engage with things that
are rooted in motivation based on greed
motivation based on a version motivation
based on careless distraction I am
actually practicing the Dharma but if I
just go around mechanically and have
hoping for results to happen to me and
certainly ignoring my responsibility for
my own choices including choice of sila
choice of practice choice of restraint
well then I'm not fixing it up even if I
actually wear robes and do everything by
the book
I'm not doing it in the right order no
they're on the right level
so you can spend the whole day again as
a layperson who doesn't necessarily as
any like you know more detailed
understanding of the citizen what to do
well you can spend the whole day being
mindful of motivation behind your
actions and before you're about to do something
and before you're about to do something
you like investigate ask yourself why
you're doing what is the purpose service
every other thing one gone for a walk
why doesn't matter shouldn't or should
matches what matters is to know why oh
well because you know the doctor told me
I need exercise
is that a valid enough reason maybe are
the determinant well easy routine
wholesome and also easy routine a loss
the virginal distraction what is rooted
in necessity why why do you need to be
alive why do you need to maintain your
health is that a goal in itself maybe
what is because you have a greater
purpose that health is required as a
basis to perform that purpose to make
you feel responsible for whatever you do
mmm then you might choose not to go for
a walk for the mattress to go pro but
either way you won't be denied regards
your choices you won't be anything you
got Direction before the speech remind
and that's practice exam where do you
know it or not whether you call it like
that or not that is really so dumb
something like whatever you have an
answer if you know that you question it
further yes thing like if you if you going on
yes thing like if you if you going on
explaining it further and further you
know you already dead start oh hold on
why am I like so keen on explanation
explaining this why am i why was I
triggered by this question because I
don't want to cover things up from it
why are you covering up always it's your
responsibility always because the
responsibilities are present
so wait that's what I said ignorance
will accumulate the burden do it the
more you ignore it the heavier it gets
mm-hmm so it seems sharper more painful
once you stop ignoring it but actually
you start D accumulating and that's how
you truly D accumulate your karma by
accepting responsibility for it you
don't be accumulating your karma by you
know making random offerings and
canceling their negative balance of your
bank account
oh yeah you're making good karma but bad
karma cannot be undone simply by
performing good cover the only way to
undo the bad karma is to fully accept
responsibility for it and then free
yourself to understanding of it
whereby doesn't apply to you and there
is no matter of action you can do to
compensate for that only freedom from
action can free you from it the good
karma can be less pressing but still
pristine that's why it's a good kamma
but it's still coming it's still a
burden and it won't last forever there
is also the good better pleasant burden
light burden agreeable good so can it's
about seeing the danger in come yeah
seen the danger in ignoring things seen
the danger in turning away from from
clarity off your motivation anyway from
the clarity of things that I felt
unpleasantly because that's why you will
turn away from clarity now because of
some universe is a mistake of the
universe no because it's unpleasant to
admit it firstly that's it
and just because of that tiny little
deep attitude
Oh Massa suffering for the under than he
has in heels and he wants to come too
many people just because of that
so the obj you know the Evita the Evita
is always in the present moment
literally hmm it's not past the VJ in a
sense that you are not maintenance for
the present Avenger
present ignoring he's where your
responsibilities and that's all you can
for yourself if you're a VJ were truly
past ignoring of things that's it that's
all abide in the past and you can not
prove that but it isn't the only reason
the past ignoring 'he's still have the
weight of ignoring this could you now
still partaking the same nature of
ignoring once you're free
yeah same with sensuality in the leopard
suit yeah where once the lepers healed
you know oh the burning embers were
always been and all the sensuality the
he remembers from before they provided
him great joy was actually paying he
sees to pass sexuality is painful all
the futures in short they would have
been would have any painful cannot step
outside of their domain it's fully
enclosed within the painful domain and
now that became apparent so it doesn't
mean like before I had the pure
sensuality when I was engaging it know
now past is seen against the backdrop of
the present understanding future is seen
against the back of the drop of the
present in sanik present is seen against
the backdrop of the present
understanding that's it